Finding Aid for Andrew Sacks photographs, 1964-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Andrew Sacks photographs, 1964-1980 1964-1980
Sacks, Andrew
1 linear feet
92847 Aa 2
Photographer from Ann Arbor, Michigan. Photographs (prints and negatives) of student demonstrations at the University of Michigan, draft card burnings and other anti-Vietnam War protests, of the riot at the 1968 Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois, of appearances of John Cage, Lyndon Johnson, Timothy Leary, Eldridge Cleaver, John Sinclair, John Lennon, Stevie Wonder, and Gerald Ford in Ann Arbor, and a meeting of Ku Klux Klan in Dearborn, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The prints were donated by Andrew Sacks (donor 6781 ) in June 1982. The negatives were donated in Oct. 1994.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
No further additions to the photographs are expected.
The collection is open for research, except that images may be released for advertising use only with the permission of the donor.
Andrew Sacks was a student at the University of Michigan from 1965 until 1969, and was a photographer for the Michigan Daily during those years. During his senior year he served as photography editor for the Daily. After graduation, Sacks remained in the Ann Arbor area, working as a freelance photographer. He maintains a website at http://www.saxpix.com/.
The collection contains prints and 35 mm negatives of photographs taken between 1964 and 1980. The photographs primarily document student protests and other student political activities at the University of Michigan, as well as some other campus activities, including political speakers and social and musical events. Some events outside of Ann Arbor are also documented, including the 1968 Democratic Convention in Chicago and a Ku Klux Klan meeting in Dearborn, Mich.
The photographs are arranged chronologically, and are described in the following list by topic and date. Some undated photographs are grouped at the end of the sequence. Although the bulk of the collection is made up of negatives, for most topics the collection also contains prints of selected frames. In some cases there are no prints, and in a few cases no negatives. The list indicates these cases.
Prints and negatives are filed in parallel sequences in the collection, both in the same order.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Civil rights.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Black Action Movement (University of Michigan); Cage, John.; Riots--Illinois--Chicago.; Cleaver, Eldridge, 1935-1998.; Dearborn (Mich.); Democratic National Convention (1968: Chicago, Ill.); Demonstrations.; Drug abuse.; Ecology.; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Ku Klux Klan (1915- ); Leary, Timothy, 1920-1996.; Lennon, John, 1940-1980.; Marijuana.; Music--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1913-1969.; Police--Illinois--Chicago.; Police--Michigan.; Political parades and rallies.; Riots.; Sinclair, John, 1941-; Slogans.; Symbols.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Students--Political activity.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements.; Wonder, Stevie.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Photography
  - Diag induction burning November 14, 1964, prints and negatives (Box 1)
  - Vietnam memorial October 16, 1965, prints and negatives
  - Veterans parade November 11, 1954, negatives only
  - Once (Again) concert, John Cage, et al. 1965, prints and negatives
  - Vietnam protest 1965, negatives only
  - Ernst Goodman, ACLU January 25, 1966, negatives only
  - Dancing--Mothers April 1966, negatives only
  - West Physics destruction July 15, 1966, negatives only
  - Diag rally--Stan Nadel September 2, 1966, negatives only
  - Sit-in November 1966, prints and negatives
  - Carl Oglesby 1966, negatives only
  - Children --Diana Oughton 1966, negatives only
  - Drug teach-in and John Sinclair January 7, 1967, prints and negatives
  - Sit-in January 11, 1967, negatives only
  - More sit-in January 18, 1967, negatives only
  - Tim Leary, medicine man February 12, 1967, prints and negatives
  - EMU protest April 6, 1967, prints and negatives
  - U Thant and Robben Fleming, Honors Convocation April 1967, negatives only
  - Diag rally, Bishop James Pike October 11, 1967, prints and negatives
  - Burnt draft card October 18, 1967, prints and negatives
  - Teach-in against war research October 30, 1967, negatives only
  - Turning in draft card at Quaker Center December 5, 1967, prints and negatives
  - Aerial photos of protest 1967, prints and negatives
  - Smoky I--Stokely Carmichel 1967, negatives only
  - Detroit love-in 1967, negatives only
  - Goss Unitube and Student Publications Building March 20, 1968, negatives only
  - McCarthy in Detroit March 22, 1968, negatives only
  - Draft card turn-in April 2, 1968, negatives only
  - Draft Board March June 4, 1968, negatives only
  - Daily RFK extra June 1968, negatives only
  - Peace March--Resistance July 1968, negatives only
  - Lyndon B. Johnson (at the VFW?) August 19, 1968, prints and negatives
  - Eldridge Cleaver August 21, 1968, prints and negatives
  - Democratic Convention August 1968, prints and negatives
  - Democratic Convention riots August 1968, prints and negatives
  - Diag rally, police at jail September 4, 1968, prints and negatives
  - Welfare--cop with cigar September 16, 1968, prints and negatives
  - State of the University message--protest September 1968, prints and negatives
  - Welfare March and rallies September 1968, negatives only
  - Welfare sit-in and violence September 1968, negatives only
  - Bursley bomb scare October 15, 1968, negatives only
  - Fleming and demonstrators November 4, 1968, prints and negatives
  - Administration Building sit-in November 5, 1968, prints and negatives
  - Winter supplement December 4, 1968, negatives only
  - People's Plaza 1968, prints and negatives
  - Canterbury House 1968, prints and negatives
  - Sesquicentennial banquet 1968, negatives only
  - Fleming tea 1968, negatives only
  - Dionysus January 26, 1969, negatives only
  - Harris and Kazarnoff winning April 8, 1969, negatives only
  - Ann Arbor street revolt June 1969, prints and negatives
  - Ann Arbor Blues Festival August 1969, negatives only
  - Repression repercussions January 1970, negatives only
  - DuPont recruiters sit-in January 1970, prints and negatives
  - Miscellaneous USSPA February 1970, negatives only
  - Street demonstration February 1970, negatives only
  - Ku Klux Klan, Dearborn February 1970, prints and negatives
  - Parsons sit-in March 1970, prints and negatives
  - Honors Assembly and stink bomb March 1970, negatives only
  - University of Michigan strike, spring 1970, prints and negatives
  - Ecology teach-in, Spring 1970, prints and negatives
  - Miscellaneous March, undercover cop May 1970, prints and negatives
  - Ecology bottle-rama June 1970, prints and negatives
  - University of Michigan vs. Dow 1970, prints and negatives
  - Peace March, Fall 1970, negatives only
  - Candlelight March, 1970, prints and negatives
  - U of M Union strike January 20, 1971, negatives only
  - Open meeting regents and protest February 1971, prints and negatives
  - University Microfilms August 1971, prints and negatives
  - Antiwar football show October 1971, prints and negatives
  - John Sinclair bailed out December 10, 1971, prints and negatives
  - John Sinclair benefit--John Lennon and Stevie Wonder December 13, 1971, prints and negatives
  - Secret police list January 1972, negatives only
  - Radicals at City Hall, Jerry DeGrieck and Nancy Wexler April 22, 1972, prints and negatives
  - Man-dug bomb crater April 22, 1972, negatives only
  - ROTC smashing April 1972, negatives only
  - Mock blood, Administration Building May 19, 1972, prints and negatives
  - Taking down Viet Cong flag May 1972, prints and negatives
  - Pun Plamondon and Genie June 1972, negatives only
  - Bomb crater at RPR July 4, 1972, prints and negatives
  - Dope at football game October 1972, prints and negatives
  - Football--Purdue and U of M November 1972, negatives only
  - Football--MSU and U of M November 1972, prints and negatives
  - Peoples Ballroom benefit at Mackinac Jack's January 1973, negatives only
  - Five dollar marijuana hearing repeal July 1973, negatives only
  - Impeach Nixon March October 1973, prints and negatives
  - Kidnapped bankers October 1974, negatives only
  - Administration Building sit-in, Feb 1975, negatives only
  - Africans kidnap coed May 1975, negatives only
  - Graduate teaching fellow strike 1975, prints and negatives
  - Gerald Ford at U of M lecture April 1977, prints and negatives
  - Anti-nuke rally, Ann Arbor 1979, prints and negatives
  - Hash Bash April 1980, prints only
  - Daily fashions undated, negatives only
  - Doug Harvey miscellaneous undated, negatives only
  - Indians undated, negatives only
  - ROTC miscellaneous undated, negatives only
  - Sit-in, miscellaneous, prints only
  - Unidentified, negatives only